(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-09T23:21:08.862184",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ときのそら生誕祭2025
新衣装お披露目
Tokino Sora Birthday Party 2025
New Outfit Reveal
いっせーのーで！
Ready, set, go!
ふわふわ！
Fuwa fuwa!
いっせーのーで！
Ready, set, go!
ふわふわ！
Fuwa fuwa!
我らの空の始まりは
The start of our sky...
触れた瞬間あらららら
...was the moment we touched, oh my, my, my!
はあ これは困った
Ah, this is trouble,
二度と元に戻らない大爆発
a big explosion that can never be undone!
そして星が生まれまして
And then, a star was born,
明け方の1番星は
the first star of dawn is...
あなたと出会った
...the one where I met you.
これは次元を揺るがす大発見
This is a dimension-shaking major discovery!
このままハート打ち上げて どこまでも高く空まで
Just like this, launching our hearts as high as the sky,
めっちゃ飛んじゃいたい！
I really want to fly away!
スタースタースタートしたこのラブは
This love that has star-star-started,
あなたがなきゃ真っ暗って
would be pitch black without you,
超新星するぞ！
it's going supernova!
満ちちゃうぞ！
It's going to overflow!
あなたに行ってしまいます
And head straight to you!
Do you understand？ スタースタースタートは分かってる
Do you understand? You know this star-star-start,
ほら目の前にずっとある一等星
look, the first-magnitude star is always right in front of you!
見てろ！
Watch me!
このビッグバンに気づいて
Notice this big bang!
愛は地球儀くらいに膨らんでこんなになってんぞ保存
My love has expanded to the size of a globe, look at it now!
想像上以上のワープは このときのためのさ
This beyond-imagination warp is all for this very moment!
いっせーのーで！
Ready, set, go!
ふわふわ！
Fuwa fuwa!
いっせーのーで！
Ready, set, go!
ふわふわ！
Fuwa fuwa!
ててて手と手 そしてあなたのハートにノーティス
H-H-Hand in hand, and notice your heart,
今の「ときので良いよ」みたいな顔して めちゃめちゃにしたい！
Making a face like "It's Tokino, so it's fine," I want to drive you crazy!
ちょっとの反応くれたら喜ぶし
If you give me even a little reaction, I'll be happy,
てかこんなの逃すなんて嘆かわしい
I mean, missing out on this is just deplorable!
我らの星の活動は
Our star activities...
割と続いて何万年保存
...have been going on for tens of thousands of years!
いや これはすごいな
Wow, this is amazing,
つまりあなたと私の創星記
in other words, the record of our star creation!
このままハートあなたごと連れて あなたを目がけて
Just like this, taking my heart along with you, aiming straight for you,
めっちゃ飛んじゃった！
I've really flown away!
スタースタースタートしたこのラブは
This love that has star-star-started,
あなたがなきゃ今頃超新星してた"
would have gone supernova by now without you,
してた！"
...it would have!
してたか？
Did it?
ほら今日まで続いて
look, it has continued until today!
Do you understand？ スタースタースタートちゃんと分かってて
Do you understand? Fully understanding this star-star-start,
急速度増して輝く一等星"
picking up rapid speed, the shining first-magnitude star!
あなたと！
...with you...
私で！
...and me...
ビッグバンしようぜ！
...let's make a big bang!
愛は地球儀くらいに膨らんでこんなになってんぞ保存
My love has expanded to the size of a globe, look at it now!
想像上以上のワープは このときのためにさ
This beyond-imagination warp is all for this very moment!
さぁ！
Now!
みんなー！
Everyone!
今日はお誕生日ライブに来てくれて、ありがとー！
Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live today!
最初に聴いてもらったのは「スタースタースタート」でしたー！
The first song you heard was "Star*Star*Start"!
みんな、コメント見えてるよー！
Everyone, I can see your comments!
はじめましての人もいっぱいコメントしてってね！
Those who are here for the first time, please leave lots of comments too!
はあ、最初からすごい気合を入れすぎましたね。
Phew, I put way too much energy into it right from the start.
というわけで、
And so...
今日は私のお誕生日です！
today is my birthday!
喉が渇きました。
My throat is dry.
あ、すみません、ありがとうございます。
Ah, sorry, thank you very much.
うん。お茶がある、美味しい。
Mmh, there's tea. It's delicious.
はい、というわけで、お水美味しいぞ。
Alright, and so, the water is delicious!
というわけで、今日のハッシュタグは、
So, today's hashtag is...
とき色の空お披露目誕生日2025です！
is "#TokiiroNoSoraOhiromeTanjoubi2025"!
ぜひトレンドにも入りたいので、よければそちらでも呟いてください。
I really want to get it trending, so please tweet using it if you'd like!
そしてですね、新衣装のお披露目や、ゲストをたくさん呼んでいるので、
Also, we have a new outfit reveal and lots of guests coming,
楽しみにしててねー！
so please look forward to it!
うぉー！
Whoo!
というわけで、今回はね、カウントダウンでも使われているアリーナに私の装飾をしてもらいました。
And so, this time, I had this arena, which is also used for countdowns, decorated with my theme!
どう？可愛いでしょ？いぇーい！
How is it? Cute, right? Yay!
そして、見て、ぬんぬんがね、
And look, Nunnun is...
4段になってるんです
It's stacked four levels high.
4段になってるのは、あの、毎年増やしてるから4段なんですね
The reason it's four levels high is... well, we increase it every year, that's why.
ってことは来年は5段になるんだな
Which means next year it will be five levels.
すごい、どんどん積まれていっちゃうね
Amazing, they're getting stacked higher and higher.
そして、あんきももですね、今回はホログラムで、ビッグサイズ！
And also, Ankimo is a hologram this time, in giant size!
でかっ！本当に大きい
Huge! It's really big.
私だけを映すと、文字しか映らないっていうビッグサイズなんですよね
It's so big that if you only show me, you can only see the letters on it.
お団子かな？そう、お団子なんですよ。ぬんぬんのことでしょう？
Is it a dango? Yes, it is. You mean Nun-Nun, right?
ちょっとね、でも、こう...文字しか...顔がね、大きくて、見えないので
But, you know... only the letters... Its face is so big we can't see it, so...
ぬんぬん！
Nun-Nun!
行くから
Here it comes.
あ、来た！ぬんぬんが来ました！
Ah, it's here! Nun-Nun has arrived!
というわけで、ぬんぬん、乗せてもらってもいいかな？いい？
So, Nun-Nun, could you let me ride on you? Is it okay?
うわー！埋まってるけどね、乗るっていうより
Wow! Though I'm sinking into it rather than riding on it.
あーい！
Yay!
ということで、こちらがあんきもの顔です
So, this is Ankimo's face.
あんきもはずっとこうやって動いています
Ankimo keeps moving like this.
そして、意外とね、つぶらな瞳なんですけど、ちゅちゅちゅってしっかりね、お目目になってるんですね
And, surprisingly, it has round eyes. They're clearly defined as eyes.
素晴らしい。うんうん、うんうん
Wonderful. Yes, yes.
そして、お、みんな、見えてるよー！
And, oh, everyone, I can see you!
会場のみんな、ありがとう！
Everyone in the venue, thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
見えてるぞー！
I can see you!
わーい！
Yay!
うわーい！
Whoa!
すごい、ぬんぬんが空を飛ばしてくれました保存
Amazing, Nun-Nun flew me through the sky.
イェーイ！
Yay!
というわけで、そんなぬんぬんが降ろしてくれた場所は、さっきと違う場所ですね
So, the place where Nun-Nun set me down is different from before.
もう一回お水を飲んだら、曲に行いたいかなと思います
After I drink some water again, I think I'd like to move on to the song.
いや、今日はね、ドキドキなんですよ。うん
Man, today I'm so nervous. Yeah.
生放送ってやっぱりドキドキしますよね
Live broadcasts really make your heart race, don't they?
なんか分かる？なんかね、さっきまで調子悪い、調子悪いって言ってたのに、今、全然調子悪くなくなっちゃった。こんなだから誰にも心配してもらえないんだ
Do you know what I mean? I was saying I felt unwell until just now, but now I don't feel bad at all. That's why nobody ever worries about me.
というわけで、次の曲、行ってましょう
So, let's go to the next song.
2曲続けて聴いてください
Please listen to these two songs back-to-back.
さくらびと
[Sakurabito]
喜びが
Joy...
舞う 春を想う 涙の羽
...dances in the spring we long for, like wings of tears.
散り行く花びらとなり
Becoming scattered petals...
あなたのもとへと
...flying to where you are.
風が鳴るたび
Every time the wind blows...
そばにいるよ
...I will be by your side.
たどり着ける
I will reach you.
悲しみより 寂しさより
More than sadness, more than loneliness...
守るべきものを今を生きる
I live in the present to protect what is dear...
あなた
...to you.
生まれ変わったら桜の下で また会いましょう
If we are reborn, let's meet again under the cherry blossoms.
きっとその時には笑い合って 永遠を誓おう
I'm sure that at that time, we will laugh together and vow eternity.
愛し愛されてこの命は 芽吹いて咲いて
Loving and being loved, this life buds and blooms...
色褪せない眼差しを胸に 舞い散る願い
With your unfading gaze in my heart, my wishes flutter down...
あなたに
...to you...
ただ咲いている
...simply blooming.
海に注ぐ
Pouring into the sea...
雨 音止む
...the rain falls silent.
待って 光はなく
Wait, there is no light,
右と左の翼は
the wings on my right and left
きつく突き揺れてる
are shaking violently.
穏やかな日々
While believing...
信じながら
in those peaceful days,
愛してると伝えたくて
I wanted to tell you that I love you,
伝わらないの 忘れてほしい
but it doesn't reach you... I want you to forget me,
明日を生きるために
so that you can live for tomorrow.
生まれ変わったら桜の下で
If we are reborn...
また会いましょう
let's meet again under the cherry blossoms.
待ち焦がれた季節の中で
In the season we've long awaited,
共に歩こう
let's walk together.
この心を染め抜いた花よ
May the flower that completely dyed my heart
あなたに届け
reach you.
誇り高き糸よ逸れて
O proud thread, drift away
名もなき風に
into the nameless wind.
大切なものはいつの時代も
That precious things, in any era,
変わらないこと
remain unchanged...
人は知りながら
Even though people know this,
過ちを
why do they keep
なぜ繰り返す
repeating their mistakes?
生まれ変わったら桜の下で
If we are reborn...
また会いましょう
let's meet again under the cherry blossoms.
きっとその時には笑って
Surely, at that time, let's smile
永遠を誓おう
and vow eternity.
愛し愛されてこの命は
Loving and being loved, this life
芽吹いて咲いて
buds and blooms.
色褪せない眼差しを胸に
With an unfading gaze in my heart,
舞い散る願い
my wishes flutter down.
あぁ あなたに
Ah, to you...
ただ逢いたくて
I just want to see you.
あぁ あなたに
Ah, to you...
ただ逢いたくて
I just want to see you.
命に嫌われている。
[Title: Hated by life itself.]
「死にたい」なんて言うなよ。
Don't say things like "I want to die."
諦めないで生きろよ。
Don't give up, live on.
そんな歌が正しいなんて馬鹿げてるよな。
To say songs like that are correct is ridiculous, isn't it?
実際自分は死んでもよくて
In reality, I don't care if I die,
周りが死んだら悲しくて
but if those around me died, I'd be sad.
それが嫌だからっていうエゴなんです。
It's just my ego saying "I don't want that."
他人が生きててもどうでもよくて
I don't care if others live,
誰かを嫌うこともファッションで
and hating someone is just a fashion.
それでも「平和に生きよう」なんて
Yet saying things like "Let's live in peace"...
素敵なことでしょう。
What a wonderful thing, right?
画面の先では誰かが死んで
Beyond the screen, someone is dying,
それを嘆いて誰かが歌って
and mourning that, someone is singing.
それに感化された少年が
Influenced by that, a boy
ナイフを持って走った。
ran off holding a knife.
僕らは命に嫌われている。
We are hated by life itself.
価値観もエゴも押し付けて
Pushing our values and egos on others,
いつも誰かを殺したい歌を
we easily broadcast songs
簡単に電波で流した。
about wanting to kill someone over the airwaves.
僕らは命に嫌われている。
We are hated by life itself.
言葉でこの傷が表せていいものか
Can these wounds really be expressed in such words?
そんなプライドばかり抱え 今日も一人ベッドに眠る
Clinging to nothing but that kind of pride, I sleep alone in bed again today.
少年だった僕たちは いつか青年に変わっていく
We who were once boys will one day turn into young men,
年老いていつか枯葉のように 誰にも知られず朽ちていく
growing old, decaying without anyone knowing, like withered leaves.
不死身の身体を手に入れて 一生死なずに生きていく
If I could obtain an immortal body and live forever without dying...
そんなSFを妄想してる
I'm fantasizing about that kind of sci-fi scenario.
自分が死んでもどうでもよくて
I don't care if I die,
それでも周りに生きて欲しくて
yet I still want those around me to live.
矛盾を抱えて生きてくなんて怒られてしまう
Living with such a contradiction, I'll surely get scolded.
「正しいものは正しくいなさい」
“Let right things be right.”
「死にたくないなら生きていなさい」
“If you don't want to die, then live.”
悲しくなるならそれでもいいなら ずっと一人で笑えよ
If you're fine with being sad, then just laugh all by yourself forever.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself.
幸福の意味すらわからず
Without even understanding the meaning of happiness,
生まれた環境ばかりを憎んで
we just hate the environment we were born into,
簡単に過去ばかりを呪う
and easily curse our own past.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself.
サヨナラばかりが多すぎて
With far too many goodbyes,
本当の別れなど知らない
knowing nothing of true farewells.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself.
幸福も 別れも 愛情も 友情も
Happiness, farewells, love, friendship—
滑稽な夢の戯れで
they're all just plays in a comical dream,
全部カネで買える代物。
all things that can be bought with money.
明日死んでしまうかもしれない。
We might die tomorrow.
すべて無駄になるかもしれない。
Everything might end up in vain.
朝も夜も春も秋も
Morning, night, spring, autumn—
変わらず誰かがどこかで死ぬ。
unchangingly, someone dies somewhere.
夢も明日も何もいらない。
I don't need dreams, tomorrow, or anything.
君が生きていたならそれでいい。
If only you were alive, that's enough.
そうだ。
Yes.
本当はそういうことが歌いたい
That's what I really want to sing about.
命に嫌われている。
Hated by life itself.
結局いつかは死んでいく。
In the end, we'll all die someday.
君だって 僕だって
You, me,
いつかは枯葉のように朽ちてく。
we'll all decay like withered leaves someday.
それでも僕らは必死に生きて
But even so, we live desperately,
命を必死に抱えて生きて
clinging desperately to our lives as we live,
転んで あがいて
falling, struggling,
泣いて 抱えて
crying, carrying on,
生きて、生きて、生きて、生きて、生きろ。
live, live, live, live, just live.
はい！ということで
All right! So,
今聞いてもらったのは「サクラミツツキ」と「命に嫌われている。」でした！
the songs you just heard were "Sakura Mitsutsuki" and "Hated by Life Itself"!
緊張しすぎて ちょっと何回か とちっちゃった！あははは！
I was so nervous, I messed up a few times! Haha!
リハの方が声出てたよ、絶対に。ね？
My voice was definitely coming out better in rehearsals. Right?
そうでしょ？カメラマンさん。え？
Right, Mr. Camera Operator? Huh?
わあ！今トレンド2位なの？
Whoa! It's currently trending at #2?
みんなありがとうーーー！
Thank you, everyone!
急なテンションの差にビビらないで。ね？
Please don't be startled by my sudden shift in mood. Okay?
ね？
Okay?
「めちゃめちゃ良かった」
“It was absolutely amazing!”
「わんこ」って言わないで！私、犬じゃないんで！
Don't call me a doggo! I'm not a dog!
ワン！
Woof!
これ美味しい。ありがとう。
This is delicious. Thank you.
「落差がすごい」ね、落差すごいよね。
“The gap in tension is crazy.” Yeah, it really is, isn't it?
いやー、でもさ、まだまだライブは始まったばっかりよ！
Man, but the concert has only just begun!
今日初めて見に来ましたよ、って人！
For anyone who's watching for the first time today...
ぜひ楽しんでってね！
Please make sure to have a great time!
いぇーい！
Yay!
ごきげん。
I'm in a great mood.
というわけで、早速次はゲストパートにいっちゃおうかな！
With that said, let's head straight into the guest segment next!
最初のゲストは...この人だ！
Our first guest is... this person!
緋月ゆい
Hidzuki Yui
はい！ということで、最初のゲストはゆいちゃんです！
All right! So, our first guest is Yui-chan!
ゆいちゃーーん！
Yui-chaaan!
そらさん？
Sora-san?
そらさん。
Sora-san.
待って。声やばい。
Wait, my voice is terrible.
そらさん、声やば！
Sora-san, your voice is crazy!
お、エコー、エコーかかってる。
Oh, the echo is on.
お、エコーかかってる、エコーかかってる。
Oh, the echo is on, the echo is on!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
すいません。本当に。この度は。
I'm sorry, really. On this occasion...
この度は本当に誠に、誠に申し訳ございませんでした。
On this occasion, I am truly and deeply sorry.
ちょっと良くなってきた？
Is it getting a bit better?
え？何ですか？
Eh? What's that?
ちょっと待って。声出てない。
Wait a second. No voice is coming out!
リハーサルの時の方が声出てた。
Your voice was better during the rehearsal.
何があったの？この数時間の間に何があったの？
What happened in these past few hours?
酷くなってますね、これ。
It's gotten much worse...
お大事に。
Please take care!
ね。ということでね、体調をちょっとね。
Right. So, you know, your health...
体調というか、喉をね。
Well, not your general health, but your throat...
とっ、咳が止まらなくなってしまって本当に。
I... I couldn't stop coughing, so really...
面白すぎる。
This is too funny.
申し訳ないです、本当に。
I'm so sorry, truly.
こんなね、晴れ舞台に、お誘いいただいたのに、本当に申し訳ないです。
You invited me to such a big stage, and I'm so sorry.
いや、ということでね、本当は今日一緒に歌う予定だったんですけど。
Well, we actually planned to sing together today...
はい、歌いたかった。
Yes, I wanted to sing.
そうなんですよ。次に歌う曲なんですけど。
That's right. The next song...
限りなく灰色へという曲をね、歌おうと思ったんですけど。
I planned for us to sing "Kagirinaku Haiiro e"...
練習したんですけど。
Even though we practiced...
うう。あのね、あの。
Aww. Actually, you see...
去年さ、3Dになったじゃん、ゆいちゃんが。で、ずっとね。
Last year, Yui-chan, you got your 3D model. And I always...
去年も呼ぼうと思ってたんだけど、去年はまだ3Dじゃなくって。で。
wanted to invite you, but you weren't in 3D yet. And...
で、歌唱の時からずっとずっとコラボしたいと思ってて。
ever since your debut, I've wanted to collab with you.
ええ、ありがとう。
Aw, thank you.
今年の誕生日には、ゆいちゃんを呼ぼう！ってすごい決めてて。
So I firmly decided to invite Yui-chan for my birthday this year!
そんなに思ってて...
You wanted that so much...
そんなに思ってたのに！
And I wanted it so badly, but...
私は、私は何をしてるんだ！
What... what on earth am I doing?!
で、その、ゆいちゃんにも合いそうな曲と思ってこの曲を選んだんですよね。
And I chose this song because I thought it would suit Yui-chan perfectly.
うう、私のために選んでくださったのに。
Ugh, you even chose it just for me...
何してんだ、バカ野郎！
What am I doing, you idiot!
いやね、でも、この、この状態でおしゃべりだけでも出てくれるのはとっても嬉しいから。
No, but even in this state, I'm so happy you came just to chat with me!
いやもう、むしろ、こんなただおしゃべりだけのために参加させていただいて。本当に...
No, I should be saying that. Thank you for letting me join just to talk...
ありがとうございます、もう。おめでとうございます！
Thank you so much, and happy birthday!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you!
だからさ、今度何かさ、配信とかじゃなくて、何か動画とか一緒に作ったりしようか。
So, next time, instead of a stream, how about we make a video together?
え？
Eh?
歌ってみた。
Like a song cover!
いやもう、恐れ多い。
Oh, that's far too kind of you!
今回のリベンジみたいな感じでさ。
Like a revenge match for this time!
はい。
Yes.
ね。
Right?
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
やろう！
Let's do it!
やりたいです。
I'd love to!
やりたいです！
We'll do it!
やった！
Yay!
やったー！
Hooray!
みんなも見たいよね？
Everyone wants to see that too, right?
見たいよね。ぺちぺち音が聞こえる。
They do. I can hear some tapping sounds.
ほっぺぺちぺちしてました。
I was tapping my cheeks.
あ、そっちのぺちぺちか。
Ah, that kind of tapping!
ほらって。
Like, "Look..."
何してんだよって。
"...what are you doing?"
いや、本当にこの出演ありがとうございました。嬉しい、本当に。
Really, thank you so much for appearing. I'm so happy.
いやもう。もうすごいもう、歌が良すぎて、私、ゲスト出る前にちょっと感極まりそうだった。
No... your singing was so amazing, I almost cried before even coming on.
いや、本当に？ありがとう。
Oh, really? Thank you!
さっき歌われてた歌が良すぎて。
The song you sang earlier was just too good.
あ、本当に？
Oh, really?
はい、感動しました。
Yes, I was so moved.
本番の方が良かったかな？
I wonder if the actual performance was better.
そうだね。
I guess so.
いや、もうめちゃくちゃ素敵でした。
No, it was absolutely wonderful.
やった、やった！
Yay, hooray!
ということでね、次の曲、二人用なんですけど、一人で頑張って
And so, the next song is for two people, but I'll do my best...
歌おうと思うので、ぜひよろしく。
...to sing it alone, so please enjoy.
応援しています。
I'll be cheering you on!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい、頑張ってください。すみません、本当に。
Yes, do your best! And I'm so sorry, really.
いや全然、全然。また一緒に遊ぼうね。
No, don't worry about it at all. Let's hang out again!
はい、ぜひ。
Yes, absolutely.
ありがとうございました、本当に。
Thank you so very much.
うん。
Yeah.
ひづきゆいちゃんでした！ペンライトも振って。
That was Hizuki Yui-chan! Wave your penlights!
ペンライトも振ります。
I'll wave mine too!
やったー！
Yay!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
ではまた一緒に話そうね。
Let's talk again sometime.
はい。失礼いたします。
Yes. Goodbye then!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
頑張ってください。
Best of luck!
またね！
See ya!
はい、また。
Yes, see you.
あ、消えちゃった。あ、消えちゃった。
Oh, she's gone. She logged off.
というわけで、まさかの一人で歌います。
So, unexpectedly, I will sing this alone.
聞いてください。
Please listen...
限りなく灰色へ。
...to "Kagirinaku Haiiro e".
限りなく灰色へ
[Song: Kagirinaku Haiiro e]
才能なんてないから ここで一生泣いているんだろう
I have no talent, so I'll probably spend my whole life crying here
目に映った景色の青さが 羨ましく思っていた
The blue of the scenery before my eyes filled me with envy
路頭に転がる人生 アスファルトの温度下がってる
A life rolling down the streets, as the asphalt temperature drops
真夜中を照らす明かりを求め つなぐ電波世界へと
Seeking a light to illuminate the midnight, connecting to the cyber world
零に 零に 求めるものだけ描いた
To zero, to zero, I drew only what I yearned for
心閉まって 待って 本当は叫びたいのよ
Locking up my heart, wait... actually, I want to scream
零に 零に 強くありたいと願った
To zero, to zero, I wished to be strong
声は無情に
My voice, heartlessly...
満ちて 孤独を奏でる指先から
From my filling fingertips playing solitude...
伝わっていく 虚ろな色
The hollow colors are spreading...
認めてはくれないの？
Won't you accept them?
くすんでしまったの灰色に こんな才能なんて借り物
They have faded into gray, this talent of mine is just borrowed.
まだ人生終わっていないから 諦めるな、って誰かの声
My life isn't over yet, "Don't give up," says someone's voice.
見失ってしまったの灰色に 気付けなくて今も抗っている
I've lost sight of it in the gray, unable to notice, I'm still fighting.
この感情奪い去ってよ 泥泥になってしまう前に
Please snatch away this emotion before it turns completely into sludge.
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and show me your love.
こんな世界とバイバイバイ
Saying bye-bye-bye to a world like this.
滲む想いなぞって描いた
I traced and drew my blurred feelings,
夢の形に泣いちゃった
and ended up crying at the shape of my dream.
いつか出来ると思ってた だけど現実（げんじつ）は残酷だろ//g,
I thought I'd be able to do it someday, but reality is cruel, isn't it?
焦りと不安の渦の間に 黒くなって浮かんでる
In the midst of impatience and anxiety, it floats, turning black.
退廃的なセンスと曖昧な表現なんかじゃ
With a decadent sense and vague expressions,
気を衒った奴らのアトリエに 飲み込まれて消えていく...
I'll be swallowed and disappear into the studios of those show-offs.
Rainy Rainy あんた流れていく泥か
Rainy Rainy, are you just mud washing away?
肩を濡らして残った 冷たい記憶の体温
The cold memory of body heat left behind, wetting my shoulders.
Rainy Rainy 雲の隙間から覗いた
Rainy Rainy, looking through the gap in the clouds,
光当たって届いて 体を軽くしたんだ
the light shone and reached me, making my body feel lighter.
美学とか プライドとか 語る前に
Before you talk about aesthetics or pride...
やれることやっていけ
Just do what you can do!
閉ざしてしまったの退路に 焼けた才能を一つ置いていけ
On the retreat path I've cut off, leave one burnt-out talent behind.
ただやったもん勝ちなんじゃないの？ 固唾飲んでればいいんじゃないの？
Isn't it first come, first served? Shouldn't you just watch with bated breath?
目を開いたって変わらない灰色に 気付いたってどうしようもないから
Even if I open my eyes, the gray won't change; even if I notice, there's nothing I can do.
それを壊したって狙っている ペルソナになって怖れ舞えよ
Even if you destroy it, you are targeted. Become a persona, fear and dance!
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and show me your love.
こんな世界とバイバイバイバイバイ
Saying bye-bye-bye-bye-bye to a world like this.
滲む想いなぞって描いた
I traced and drew my blurred feelings,
言の葉の実 飲み込んで
swallowing the seeds of my words.
くすんでしまったの灰色に こんな才能なんて借り物
They have faded into gray, this talent of mine is just borrowed.
まだ人生終わっていないから 諦めるな、って誰かの声
My life isn't over yet, "Don't give up," says someone's voice.
見失ってしまったの灰色に 気付けなくて今も抗っている
I've lost sight of it in the gray, unable to notice, I'm still fighting.
この感情奪い去ってよ 泥泥になってしまう前に
Please snatch away this emotion before it turns completely into sludge.
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and show me your love.
こんな世界とバイバイバイバイバイ
Saying bye-bye-bye-bye-bye to a world like this.
滲む想いなぞって描いた
I traced and drew my blurred feelings,
夢の形は笑っていた
and the shape of my dream was laughing.
はい！皆さんありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you very much, everyone!
いや、一回一回お水を飲まないと、息が切れてしまいますな。
Wow, if I don't drink water after every song, I'll completely run out of breath.
にゃーい！にゃーいじゃない。
Yay! Wait, not "yay"!
反応してしまった。はーいって。
I ended up responding to it. Saying "Hello"!
いや、というわけで、ゲストをまだまだ見たいよね？ということで、どんどん行っちゃいましょうか！
Well, so, you still want to see more guests, right? So let's keep on going!
続いてのゲストは、この人です！
Our next guest is this person!
白い薔薇の花びら ひとつふたつ開けば
If one or two petals of a white rose open,
あの日の記憶 蘇るでしょう
the memories of that day will surely return.
安らぎに照らされて 花を咲かせた夜は
The night when the flower bloomed, illuminated by peace,
甘く切なく 色づいていく
sweetly and painfully, starts to gain color.
光る糸 辿るように
As if tracing a shining thread,
時は静かに流れて
time flows quietly by.
満ち引き 揺れに沿いながら
Following the ebb and flow, the swaying,
人は生まれ変わる
people are reborn.
あなたの微笑みは 胸を融かす温もり
Your smile is a warmth that melts my heart,
どこかで見た 甘い夢 of you
like a sweet dream I've seen somewhere before.
沈む夕日 今を切り取られても
Even if the sinking sun carves away the present,
二人の影は 重なってゆく
our shadows overlap.
果てしなく遠く 限りなく深く
Infinitely distant, endlessly deep,
交わった運命のように
like our intertwined destinies.
何度も掴んで 何度も失って
Taking hold again and again, losing again and again,
やっと巡り会えたこと
we've finally found each other.
空が地を求め 花が雨を待ち
Just as the sky seeks the earth, and flowers wait for rain,
夜が明日を乞うように
just as the night begs for tomorrow...
二つの心が 一つだったこと
Our two hearts were once one,
こんなにも求めていたの
which I've yearned for so deeply.
互い眠り解いて 今宵巡り会えたなら
Awakening each other from sleep, if we meet tonight,
二人のロンド さあ踊りましょう
let's dance our rondo.
過ぎた日々を流すように
As if washing away the days gone by,
月は優しく潤んで
the moon is gently misty.
記憶の先にもう一度
Once more, beyond my memories,
愛しさが溢れた
love overflowed.
あなたの年月を 双眸に愛せるなら
If I can cherish your years in my eyes,
激動だって 守っていたい
I want to protect you even through turbulence.
吹き迷う風 二人を遠ざけても
Even if the wild wind drives us apart,
信じることを 忘れないで
please don't forget to believe.
褪せない煌めき 儚い揺らめき
Unfading radiance, fleeting shimmering,
漂う幻のように
like a drifting illusion.
彷徨いながらも 変わらない場所へ
Though we wander, to that unchanging place,
やっと辿り着いたこと
we've finally arrived.
闇が陽を奪い 嘘が罪になり
Even if darkness steals the sun, and lies become sins,
過去が未来を裂いても
and even if the past tears the future apart,
巡りゆくように きっとこの場所を
as the cycle turns, surely this place
私は選んでいたの
is the one I had chosen.
みんな！盛り上がってこうねー！
Everyone! Let's pump it up!
コメントたくさんありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for all the comments!
果てしなく遠く 限りなく深く
Infinitely distant, endlessly deep,
交わった運命のように
like our intertwined destinies.
何度も掴んで 何度も失って
Taking hold again and again, losing again and again,
やっと巡り会えたこと
we've finally found each other.
空が地を求め 花が雨を待ち
Just as the sky seeks the earth, and flowers wait for rain,
夜が明日を乞うように
just as the night begs for tomorrow...
二つの心が 一つだったこと
Our two hearts were once one,
こんなにも求めていたの
which I've yearned for so deeply.
白い薔薇の花びら 一つ二つ散る時
When the white rose petals fall, one by one,
優しい朝に 染められるでしょう
they will surely be painted by the gentle morning light.
時を経て生まれ変わって あなたの胸に咲けば
Reborn across time, if I bloom in your chest,
二人の愛は 永遠になる
our love will become eternal.
はい！ありがとうございます！
Yes! Thank you so much!
二人目のゲストは、AZKiちゃんだよ！
Our second guest is AZKi-chan!
みなさん、AZKiです！こんばんはー！
Everyone, I'm AZKi! Good evening!
そらちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thank you for inviting me!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
コラボとかはしてるけど、こういう風に一緒にやるのは、2年前の配信以来？
We do collabs and all, but performing together like this, is it the first time since that stream two years ago?
100万人の… そうそうそう！
The 1 million subscribers one... Yes, yes, yes!
だから、しかも二人で歌うのは相当久しぶりじゃない？
So, plus, singing together as a duo has been quite a while, hasn't it?
もっと前だよ！もっと前だよ！
It's even longer than that! Even longer!
なんか懐かしいって感じがする。
It feels kind of nostalgic.
ちょっとさ、
Hey, listen...
何？
What?
ネイル見せよう。ネイル？
Let's show our nails. / Nails?
青です
It's blue.
紫です
It's purple.
頑張って塗ったよ
I worked hard to paint them.
ねー！おしゃれしたよ！
Yeah! We dressed up!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いやあの、あんきももね、積み上がって…あんきもじゃないよ
No, well, Ankimo is also piled up... wait, not Ankimo.
ヌンヌンもね、積み上がってますけれども
Nunnun is also piled up, but...
2017年から、8年目？
Since 2017, we're in our 8th year?
そうだね
That's right.
になって、葵ね、数えたんですよ。そらちゃんとの共演を。
And I, Aoi, actually counted our collaborations.
おっ！
Oh!
あの、生放送の雑談コラボとかそういうのはなしで、
Excluding things like casual talking collabs on live streams...
31回！
31 times!
そんなにやってる！？うわーー！
We did that many!? Wow!
でも、葵調べだから、ちょっと分かんないけど、ざっくり、ざっくりそんな感じだった。
But that's just by my own count, so I'm not totally sure, but roughly, roughly that many.
すごい！
Amazing!
本当にね、いや、だから配信とか、その100万人の祝いとかも入れたら、もっともっともっと、
Really, so if we include streams like the 1 million subscribers celebration, it'd be way, way more.
一緒にやらせていただいてるな、バディだからさ、私たち。
that we've done together. Because we are buddies, after all.
私たちバディだから。8年目だから。葵の顔もだんだんこう、ヌンヌンと一緒に積み上げてくれないかな？
We're buddies. It's our 8th year. So I wonder if my face will gradually be piled up alongside Nunnun's?
怖い、怖い！隣とかでいいから。
That's scary, scary! Even just next to him is fine.
怖い！
Scary!
いや、すごいね。だってもう歴史がさ、ステージにも散りばめられていて。
It's amazing, though. Because our history is scattered all over this stage.
ねえ、すごいでしょ？めっちゃヌンヌン浮いてるの。星もあるし。
Right, isn't it amazing? Nunnun is floating all over. There are stars too.
これ4つ、そう、4つ。あんきももね、ちゃんとあの、曲のリズムによって、こうやってやってるんですよ。
Four of them, yes. And Ankimo is moving like this to the rhythm of the music too.
すごい、キュート。
So cute!
ゆっくりなったりとか、速くなったり。あんきもも頑張ってるなと思って。
Slowing down, speeding up. Ankimo is working hard too.
そう、あんきもめっちゃ頑張ってくれる。どうですか？お誕生日の気分。
Yeah, Ankimo is working really hard. How are you feeling on your birthday?
いや、もうなんかね、さっきまですごいドキドキしてたんだけど、今はこうやってみんなに、こう、お祝いされて、めっちゃ嬉しい。
Well, I was actually so nervous until just now, but now being celebrated by everyone like this, I'm so happy.
みんな、たくさんたくさんコメントしてってね！
Everyone, please leave lots and lots of comments!
すごいよ、もう、そらちゃんへの愛がね。そらともさんのそらちゃんへの愛がもう、
It's incredible, the love for Sora-chan. The Soratomo's love for Sora-chan is already...
葵ちゃんとはバディですから。よろしくお願いします。
Aoi-chan and I are buddies. Let's keep it up!
いっぱいコメントしてね、いっぱい。
Please leave lots of comments, lots of them!
呟いてよ、よろしく！
And tweet about it, please!
葵もこの後も見守ってるからね。
I'll be watching over you afterwards too.
やったー！
Yay!
また遊ぼうね。あ、あと新衣装ね。
Let's hang out again. Ah, and the new outfit!
あ、そう、楽しみにしてるから、遊ぼうね。遊ぼう！
Ah, yes! I'm looking forward to it, let's play! Let's play!
またねー！ありがとう！頑張ってー！
See you later! Thank you! Good luck!
バイバーイ。
Bye-bye!
なにその、予想外すぎる。
What was that? So unexpected.
というわけで、相変わらず仲良しの葵ちゃんでした。
And that was Aoi-chan, who is as close to me as ever.
それでは続いてのゲストに行きましょう。続いてのゲストはこの人です。
Now, let's move on to the next guest. The next guest is this person!
ゲスト 彩音
[Guest: Ayane]
信じてた 信じられた そのすべてを 今始めよう
I believed, I was believed in... let's start it all right now
不器用な この勇気は コンプレックスを 今...
This clumsy courage of mine... now, my complex...
乾いた風が 追いかける波のように
Like waves chased by the dry wind
音を立て背中を 押し続けた
Making a sound and constantly pushing my back
耳を澄ませば
If you listen closely
ざわめくロジック
A rustling logic
新しい その場所への扉を 開け放って
Open wide the door to that new place
切なくて愛おしいこと
Painful yet precious things
思いは時空を超えて
Our feelings transcend space and time
Together ずっと心は そばにある
Together, our hearts will always be side-by-side
大切なあの陽だまりが
That precious sunny spot
刹那に散り行く景色
A scenery scattering in an instant
今すべてを その力を 与えたまえ
Now grant all of that power unto me
僕は瞳をそらさずに
Without averting my eyes
傷も涙も真実も
I will face the wounds, the tears, and the truth
温かいその雫が透明なら力となり
If those warm drops are transparent, they will become my strength.
もしそれが深紅ならばコンプレックス・イマージュ
But if they are crimson, they become a complex image.
手探りの道 絡み合うラビリンス
A path felt out in the dark, an intertwining labyrinth.
離れていても聞こえる声
A voice I can hear even when we are apart.
目には見えない確かなオブリゲーション
An unseen, yet certain obligation.
もう二度と迷わないと誓えるこの想い
These feelings that make me swear I'll never wander again.
遥かなる社の神よ
Oh, gods of the distant shrine,
祈りがもし届くなら
if my prayers can reach you,
重ねた ここに僅かな五芒星
let them overlap here in a faint pentagram.
戸惑いはもう何もなく
Now all hesitation is gone,
導く光のままに
following where the guiding light leads.
今すべての悲しみを捨てて
Now, casting aside all sadness,
僕は瞳を逸らさずに
I will not avert my gaze,
傷も涙も真実も
from the wounds, the tears, and the truth.
切なくて愛おしいほど想いは時空を越えて
So painful yet so precious, my feelings transcend time and space,
溶け出す 澄んだ心は傍にある
melting down, my clear heart is right by your side.
大切なあの陽だまりが刹那に散りゆく景色
That precious sunny spot, a scenery scattering in an instant.
今すべての力を与えたまえ
Now, grant me all of your strength,
僕は瞳を逸らさずに
I will not avert my gaze,
傷も涙も真実も
from the wounds, the tears, and the truth.
はい！聴いていただいたのは「コンプレックス・イマージュ」でした！
Yes! What you just heard was "Complex Image"!
そして、ゲストに来ていただきました、彩音さんです！
And we have a special guest with us, Ayane-san!
彩音です！そらともの皆さん、初めまして！
I'm Ayane! Everyone in Soratomo, nice to meet you!
彩音です！
I'm Ayane!
今日は来ていただいて、本当に本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so, so much for coming today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
嬉しすぎてもうテンションが上がってしまっていますが...
I'm so incredibly happy, my hype is off the charts right now...
私もです！
Me too!
本当ですか！ありがとうございます！
Really? Thank you so much!
今回、彩音さんに来ていただいたのは、えっと、私、なんと恐れ多くも「コンプレックス・イマージュ」をカバーさせていただきまして。
The reason I invited Ayane-san today is, well, I actually had the great honor of covering "Complex Image"...
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
それに反応していただいたのがとっても嬉しくて、ぜひぜひコラボで歌わせていただけたら嬉しいなと思って、お呼びいたしました！
And I was so thrilled when you responded to it, so I reached out hoping we could sing it together in a collab!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
まさか来てくれるなんて思ってなくて、もう今、ドキドキが止まらないんですけど...
I never imagined you'd actually come, and now my heart won't stop racing...
私もです！今すごい心拍数が上がってます！
Me too! My heart rate is incredibly high right now!
本当に本当に、もう、素敵な歌声で。もう、私、ずっとこうやって聴いていようかなって途中から思っちゃいました。
Your voice is just so, so beautiful. Halfway through, I caught myself thinking I should just stand here and listen to you.
いやいや、一緒に歌っていただいてありがとうございます！
Oh no, thank you so much for singing it with me!
いや、なんかライブでこういう風に一緒に歌えるとは思わなかったんですけど、どうでしょう、こういう大きいステージで一緒に歌うのは？
I never thought we'd get to sing together like this at a live concert. How did it feel singing together on such a big stage?
嬉しいです。あの、そらさんは横浜アリーナが目標なんですよね？
I'm so happy. Sora-san, your goal is Yokohama Arena, right?
はい！はい！そうです！
Yes! Yes! That's right!
いつか、その夢が叶った時に、ご一緒できたら嬉しいです！
When that dream comes true someday, I'd be so happy to join you there!
えっ、いい、いいんですか？いいんですか？
Wait, really? Are you sure? Is that okay?
はい！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! I'd love to!
また歌ってくれるんですか？
You'll sing with me again?!
はい、もちろんです。
Oh, yes, of course!
えっと、とっても嬉しいです。
I'm really, really happy!
もう本当に、ずっと、ずっと聴いていた曲で、ほかの曲もめちゃくちゃ聴いているので...
I've been listening to this song forever, and I listen to your other songs all the time, so...
嬉しいです。ありがとうございます。
I'm so glad. Thank you so much.
本当に、大好きな方に、こう、生誕祭に来ていただけて、もう私、感謝でいっぱいです。
I'm just so grateful that someone I admire so much could come to my birthday celebration.
今後とも、よろしくお願いします。
I look forward to working with you in the future.
今後とも、ぜひよろしくお願いします！
Yes! I look forward to it too!
また、なんかコラボとかできたら、とっても嬉しいなと思います。
I'd be so happy if we could collaborate again sometime.
ぜひ！よろしくお願いします。
Absolutely! I'd love to.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
改めまして、そらさんお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, happy birthday, Sora-san!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ということで、
So...
本日はあやねさんに来ていただきました。
Ayane-san joined us today.
本当に、本当に、ありがとうございました！
Thank you so, so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you!
緊張した！
I was so nervous!
緊張したよ。
I was really nervous.
みんなにも緊張が伝わってたよね。
I'm sure you could tell how nervous I was.
緊張も上手く言えない。
I couldn't even say "nervous" properly.
あ、トレンド1位になったの？！
Wait, we hit trending #1?!
うそ！
No way!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
というわけで、あの、お誕生日配信も終盤に近づいてきたんですけども、えっと...
So, we're nearing the end of this birthday stream, but, um...
いや、感無量すぎて、何も言えない。あ...
Honestly, I'm so overwhelmed with emotion, I can't even speak. Ah...
でも、まだ、まだまだ！先があるよね！みんな！
But wait, there's more, much more to come! Everyone...
新衣装、見たいよね！
You want to see my new outfit, right?!
というわけで、新衣装お披露目の時間だよ！
So, it's time for the new outfit reveal!
みんな、準備はいい？！
Everyone, are you ready?!
行くよ！3、2、1... あ、声が...
Here we go! 3, 2, 1... Ah, my voice...
へへへ。へへへ。
Hehehe. Hehehe.
ちらっ、ちらっ、ちらっ、ちらっ。
Peek, peek, peek, peek...
いえーい。
Yay!
ひょーう！あははは。
Hyoo! Hahaha!
どう？ちょっと見えた？
How is it? Did you see a little bit?
ちょっと見えた？ちょっと見えたよね？！
Did you see a little? I'm sure you did!
手しか見えない。きゃっ。あはは。
Only my hand is visible. Kya! Haha.
あ、おめでとう、みんなありがとう。
Ah, congrats, thank you everyone!
みんな「見たい」って言って！
Everyone, say "We want to see it!"
せーの！
Ready, go!
もっともっと！「見たい！見たい！」
More, more! "We want to see it! We want to see it!"
聞こえないぞ！「見たい！」
I can't hear you! "We want to see it!"
あ、素晴らしいみんな！
Ah, you're all wonderful!
では行きますよ。
Here we go, then.
3、2、1、オープン！
3, 2, 1, open!
はい、ということでどうかな？今回の新衣装です！
All right! So, what do you think? Here's my new outfit!
なんとね、これね、あの、テーマが書いてもらえてて、
And get this, they actually wrote down the theme for it...
何だと思う？テーマ。
What do you think the theme is?
読みますね。「モノトーン絶対領域パンツ」
I'll read it: "Monotone absolute territory pants."
どういうこと？！どういうこと？！あはははは！
What does that even mean?! What does that mean?! Hahaha!
というわけで、今回はですね、ちょっとショートヘアに憧れちゃいまして、私ちょっと、ショートヘアのウィッグを、
So, this time, I was longing for short hair, so I got a short hair wig...
手に入れちゃいました！
I got my hands on one!
どう？ショートヘア初めてだから、ちょっと緊張してるんだけど、
What do you think? It's my first time having short hair so I'm a bit nervous...
似合うかな？似合うかな？
Does it suit me? Does it suit me?
どういうこと？何てテーマだ。多分、これが「絶対領域」ってことなんじゃないかな。
What does that mean? What a theme. I guess this part is the "absolute territory."
でね、他にもいろんなものがあるんですけど、
And, there are other elements too, but...
それは、配信後のアフターライブ、メンバー限定で見せちゃおうかなって思ってるから、
I'm thinking of showing them during the after-live for members only after the stream.
ぜひ、そっちも観たいなっていう人はメンバーに来てくれると嬉しいな。
So if you want to see them too, I'd love for you to join the membership.
はい！というわけで
Yes! And so,
新衣装で歌っていこうかなって思います！
I think I'll sing a song in my new outfit!
新衣装似合ってるかな？ドキドキしちゃう
Does it suit me? I'm so nervous!
いきますよ！
Here I go!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン！
Electrical Surfin'!
みんな！サーフィン！サーフィン！とか
Everyone! If you know the parts like "Surfin'! Surfin'!"
ジャンプとか知ってる人は一緒に言ってね！
or jumping, say it along with me!
不条理不確定の海は今日も 晴れ時々雪ところによりパフェ
The absurd and uncertain sea is today... sunny, sometimes snowy, with parfait in some areas!
前人未到の波に乗って またどこかのあなたを待機中
Riding an unprecedented wave, I'm waiting for you somewhere again
偶然だって必然のうち 核心確信は見えない糸でしょう
Even coincidences are a part of fate, core convictions are like invisible threads, right?
完全個性が惹かれるから エンタースペース駆け抜ける
Since complete personalities attract each other, we run through the enter space
タタップ
Tap, tap!
ここは0と1の楽園
Here is a paradise of 0 and 1
タタップ
Tap, tap!
広く深い世界から見つけ出して
Find me in this wide and deep world
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン こちらにきてきて 酸いも甘いもいただきます
Electrical surfin', surfin', come over here, I'll take the sour with the sweet!
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手とって手
Surfin', surfin', hand in hand,
年中無休で踊り明かしましょう
let's dance all night, 365 days a year!
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はいはい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey, Hey!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
攻略手探りの海は今日も 赤青緑でとにかく一杯一杯
The sea of groping for strategies is today... full of red, blue, and green anyway!
悠々自適の波に乗って お待ちかねのいつもの開始中
Riding the easygoing wave, the long-awaited usual routine is starting
そんなこんなどんなもんなあんなようなこと くだらなさこそが至福の鍵でしょう
This, that, what, and things like those, absurdity is surely the key to supreme bliss
のんびりぐーたらであーだこーだ行こう コマンドデリートでレスポンス
Let's go lazily and chat about this and that, command delete for response
タタップ
Tap, tap!
ここは雲の向こうの未来
Here is the future beyond the clouds
タタップ
Tap, tap!
狭く暗い部屋じゃもう物足りないの
A small, dark room is no longer enough
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン こちらにきてきて 酸いも憂いも忘れてさ
Electrical surfin', surfin', come over here, forgetting the sourness and worries
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手とって手
Surfin', surfin', hand in hand,
年中無休に狂えを覚えてて
remember to go crazy 365 days a year!
せーの、サーフィン！
One, two, surfin'!
もっとサーフィン！サーフィン！
More surfin'! Surfin'!
もっと！サーフィン！サーフィン！
More! Surfin'! Surfin'!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン こちらを見てみて 空に輝く奇跡の輪
Electrical surfin', surfin', look over here, the ring of miracles shining in the sky
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手とって手
Surfin', surfin', hand in hand,
ウェルカム夢中で飛べ！飛べ！飛べ！飛べ！飛べ！飛べ飛べ飛べ！
welcome daze, jump! Jump! Jump! Jump! Jump! Jump, jump, jump!
サーフィン サーフィン こちらにきてきて 酸いも甘いもいただきます
Surfin', surfin', come over here, I'll take the sour with the sweet!
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手とって手
Surfin', surfin', hand in hand,
年中無休で踊り明かしましょう
let's dance all night, 365 days a year!
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はいはい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey, Hey!
はい！ということで、ありがとうございました！
Yes! So, thank you very much!
ありがとうございます
Thank you!
いやー！盛り上がる曲、いっぱい踊れるようなね、イメージで
Wow! A hype song, made with the image of being able to dance a lot,
新衣装作ったので
since I made this new outfit.
次のゲストパートでもどんな感じになるかな？っていうのを見ていこうと思います
So I'd like to see how it'll be in the next guest part too!
次が最後のゲストパートです！
Next is the final guest part!
告知を見てくれた人なら分かるよね？
If you saw the announcement, you know who it is, right?
この人たちです！
It's these people!
【ゲスト：儒烏風亭らでん、轟はじめ】
[GUESTS: Juufuutei Raden, Todoroki Hajime]
【ステージスタート】
[STAGE START]
誰もが突然に始まった
Everyone suddenly started
デタラメなシナリオの上で
on a nonsense scenario.
それは映画のような まるで映画のような
It's like a movie, just like a movie,
どこにでもあるストーリー
a story you can find anywhere.
間違いだらけの道のりだ
It's a journey full of mistakes
丸付けられるのは幾つだ
how many can be marked with a circle?
何が良くないのか どこが良くないのか
What's not good, where is not good?
そこまで教えてくれよ
Tell me that much!
明け方の防波堤
Breakwater at dawn,
妄想性の逃避行
delusional escape,
勘違いの英雄ごっこ
playing a misunderstood hero,
もう渋帯してんだ どうしようもこうしようもないよな
it's already congested, there's nothing we can do about it, right?
こんなはずじゃなかったよなって
"It wasn't supposed to be like this," you say
どんなはずだったんだよなって
"How was it supposed to be?" you say
思えば思うほど
The more I think about it,
いや、これじゃない ない ない 嵌まり役は割に合わない
no, this isn't it, it's not, it's not, the fitting role is not worth it.
向いてない ない 今すぐやめてしまうか
"I'm not cut out for this," should I just quit right now?
そりゃない ない いつになれば僕は
No way, when will I finally...
主役になれるんだろうな
...be able to become the main character?
足りなくなるたび笑ったり
Laughing whenever things run short,
増えた荷物数えては泣いたりで
weeping as I count my growing baggage.
大層なことでもないばかり
Nothing is really a big deal,
責めることすらできず悩んだり
struggling without even being able to blame anyone.
燦々と輝く街の灯り
The brilliantly shining city lights,
散々だって顔の通りすがり
and the passersby with miserable faces.
始めるなら今そうだろな
If I'm to start, it has to be now, right?
またやろう やろう やろう
Let's do it again, and again, and again.
これじゃない ない 嵌まり悪いようだ
This isn't it, it doesn't seem to fit.
向いてない ない 今すぐやめてしまえば
I'm not cut out for this, if I just quit right now,
でも何万回と繰り返した
but after repeating it tens of thousands of times,
明日に期待してしまうか
will I end up expecting something from tomorrow?
あこがれた空想の飛行船 勘違いの英雄ごっこ
The imaginary airship I yearned for, playing a misunderstood hero.
渋滞してんだ どうしようもない こうしようもないような
It's congested, there's nothing that can be done either way.
あの頃は確かにあったんだ 描き出したものがあったんだ
Back then, it was certainly there, there was something I drew out.
いつの間にか僕は
Without me realizing, I've...
誰もが 突然に始まった
Suddenly, for everyone, it began.
出鱈目なシナリオの上で
On top of a nonsensical scenario,
何かを演じるの 誰かを演じるの
performing something, playing someone,
そんなわけがないだろう
there's no way that's how it is.
まだこれじゃ まだここじゃ ない ない
Not yet like this, not here yet, no, no.
終わりじゃないから
Because this isn't the end.
向いてない ない なら書き換えてしまえよ
If I'm not cut out for this, then I'll just rewrite it.
ほら大体いついつまでもきっと
Look, surely, forever and ever,
主役は僕らだけだろ
we are the only main characters, right?
いつの日か
Someday...
バイバイ 終わりは来るから
Bye-bye, because the end will come.
拍手喝采 笑顔で終わらせよう
A round of applause, let's end it with a smile.
描きたい未来はここにあった
The future I wanted to draw was right here.
思うままに 好きにするがいい
Just as you please, do as you like.
これはそうだ
This is, indeed...
最低辺から駆け上がった 映画のようなストーリー
...a movie-like story, running up from the very bottom.
はい！ということで最後のゲストは、はじめちゃんとらでんちゃんのらではじコンビ！
Alright! So, our final guests are Hajime-chan and Raden-chan, the Radehaji duo!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ぽぽぽん！らではじかちこりヴィクトリーゴージャス番長！轟はじめちょ！
Po-po-pon! Radehaji Kachikori, Victory Gorgeous, Bancho! Todoroki Hajime-cho!
はい！じゅ、て…全然身だしな…じゅーて、らでんでございます！
Yes! Juu... te... Completely untidy... Juufuutei Raden here!
そして先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！ / おめでとうございます！
And Senpai, happy birthday! / Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！そして、新衣装！ / めっちゃいい！すごーい！
Thank you very much! And also, the new outfit! / It's so good! Amazing!
え、ぜひちょっとスクショなど撮りたいなと思うんですけど
Hey, I'd really love to take some screenshots!
あ、ポーズ！カメラマンはじめちゃん？ / あ、じゃあ、お持ちカメラ、カメラ…
Ah, poses! Is Hajime-chan the photographer? / Ah, then, my camera, camera...
先輩が撮られるほう、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ… / あ、そういうこと！
Senpai is the one being photographed, wait, wait, wait... / Ah, I see!
かわいいな！ / じゃあはじめからポーズして何か撮っちゃったり…
So cute! / Then let's pose from the beginning and take some...
そら先輩の、て、て、て、TTポーズ？ TTポーズみたいな！
Sora-senpai's... T-T-T-TT pose? Like a TT pose!
お、いいね。TTポーズ！
Oh, nice! TT pose!
この、このラインがいいですね、このラインが！
This, this line is great, this line!
シンプルな衣装だからこそ映えるね！ / おお、え、ちょっとポージング。
Because the outfit is simple, it really stands out! / Ooh, let's pose a bit.
この絶対領域の部分とかも…
This absolute territory part too...
あら、いいですね！あー！
Oh, that's nice! Ah!
すごい！なんか、なんだろ、ベルトみたいな感じになって… / めちゃめちゃ素敵！
Amazing! It's like a garter belt or something... / It's so wonderful!
そうそうそう。 / じゃ、ちょっとらでんからも、ちょっと見返り美人のポーズなんて、しちゃってもいいですか？
Right, right, right. / Then, could I ask you for a "looking-back beauty" pose too?
お、呼んだ？ / あー！めちゃめちゃいい！
Oh, did you call? / Ah! That's so good!
これには菱川師宣もにっこりですよ！
Even Hishikawa Moronobu would smile at this!
ひしかわもの…（笑）
Hishikawa Mono... (laughs)
見返り美人の、見返り美人のひとつ！
One of the looking-back beauties!
すごい！めっちゃいい！
Amazing! So good!
みんなスクショ撮れた？撮れたかな？
Did everyone get their screenshots? I hope you did!
なんか、髪型も…脇、脇見せて！そら先輩、脇、脇、あ、あ、あ
And the hairstyle... show us your armpit! Sora-senpai, armpit, armpit, ah, ah, ah
そら先輩の脇が！
Sora-senpai's armpit!
どういうこと！？見えちゃった！
What do you mean?! It showed!
めっちゃいい！
So good!
イェーイ！
Yay!
え、３人でも撮りたい！
Hey, I want to take one with the three of us!
え、いいですか？ / じゃあ…
Oh, can we? / Then...
じゃ、じゃーん！
Ta-da!
髪型、ショート同士！
Our hairstyles are both short!
あ、ほんとだ、お揃い！
Oh, you're right, we match!
なん、いいな、なんか、なんかいいな！
Somehow, this is nice, somehow it's really nice!
服装、モノトーン同士！
Our outfits are both monotone!
一人だけ清潔感バグった人いるんだけど！
There's one person whose sense of cleanliness is totally bugged out!
違う違う違う！そんなことない、そんなことない！
No, no, no! That's not true, that's not true!
外見は、外見は！
On the outside, at least on the outside!
あ、ちょうどいい、ちょうどいい！助けて！
Ah, perfect timing, perfect timing! Save me!
ちょうどいいね！レスキュー！
Perfect indeed! Rescue!
というわけで...
And so...
お二人と一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったし
I was so happy to sing together with both of you...
これからも仲良くしてほしいです！
and I hope we can keep getting along!
よろしくお願いします！
We look forward to it!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Nice to meet you!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
皆様お邪魔しました！ありがとうございました！
Sorry for the intrusion, everyone! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！失礼します！
Thank you very much! Goodbye!
じゃ、我々は...ではまた皆さん！
Well, we shall... See you later, everyone!
え？
Eh?
その去り方は斬新すぎる！
That way of leaving is way too novel!
あんきもの中に消えちゃったよ！
They disappeared right into Ankimo!
というわけで、ライブも終盤に近づいてきましたが
And so, the live concert is approaching its end,
最後まで盛り上がっていこう！
but let's keep the hype up until the very end!
次の曲を聴いてください、UNDEAD。
Please listen to the next song, UNDEAD.
歩む 歩む 歩むのよ
Walking, walking, walking on,
人ならざるものも
even those who are not human.
絶えず目指せよ 生きている証
Always strive for proof that you are alive.
目を逸らした過去も
Even the past you turned your eyes away from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future ahead,
カウンセリング やれやれ
counseling them all, oh dear.
古今東西 ピースピース
All times and places, peace, peace!
ねぇねぇねぇ
Hey, hey, hey,
なんだかどうして
for some reason, why does it feel like
戦っているような気がするの
I'm constantly fighting?
誰と誰と誰と戦うの
Who, who, who am I fighting?
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分
My past self, my self, my self, my self.
もうとうに死んでる
The battle against the transparent ghost
透明な亡霊と対決
that has already died long ago.
痛い 痛い 痛い記憶の奥
Deep inside the painful, painful, painful memories,
何故？もういないのに あれ？
why? Though they are no longer here, huh?
そっちが良い アイロニー
"That side is better," what an irony.
乗っ取られかけているのは 今の自分
The one about to be taken over is my current self.
何故？消えない劣等感 (yes!)
Why? The persistent inferiority complex (yes!),
弱い コンプレックス
and my weak complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It's as if I am possessed by it,
へばりついたまま
clinging onto me,
まだ 離れない
and still won't let go,
コメント！
Comments!
書いて言ってくれてる気がする。
I feel like you've been writing a lot.
順番に紹介していくよ！
I'll introduce them one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First, this one!
「夢のそらばワンマン」ファブリックポスター！
The "Yume no Sora-ba Solo Concert" Fabric Poster!
私が歌唱しているワンシーンを切り取った
It captures a scene of me singing,
エモエモのファブリックポスターです！
making it a very emotional fabric poster!
紙のポスターとは違って折れたりする心配もないですし
Unlike paper posters, there's no need to worry about it creasing,
ま、長く飾ってくれるかな？ということで
and you can display it for a long time. So,
お部屋のサイズに合わせてね、折ったり畳んだりして飾ることもできると思うので
you can fold or tuck it to fit your room's size,
ぜひぜひみんな部屋に飾ってね！
so please display it in your room!
続いては、こちら！
Next up is this one!
そらとおそろい2Wayネックレス！
The "Matching with Sora" 2-way Necklace!
ということで、今回の新衣装でもしているネックレスのおそろっちが
I wanted us to have matching necklaces, like the one
作りたいなと思って、おそろっちのものを用意しました
I'm wearing with my new outfit, so I made this matching item.
え、ただね、あの「ネックレスはしないよ」って人のために
But for those who don't usually wear necklaces,
ちょっとチャーム部分を取り外すことができる2Way仕様になってまして// （※原文：2way仕様）
you can detach the charm, thanks to the 2-way design.
ほら、バッグとかにワンポイントでも
So, you can attach it as an accent on your bag,
つけて、一緒におそろっちっていう風にできるようにしました
and we can still be matching together!
そして続いては、こちら！
And next is this one!
そらのバンダナハンカチ！イェーイ！
Sora's Bandana Handkerchief! Yay!
おそろい柄のハンカチ。今回はね、みんなとおそろっちっていうのをテーマに
A matching-pattern handkerchief. This time, our theme was "matching with everyone,"
作ってみました！
so I created this!
シンプルなデザインなので日常でも使えますし
It has a simple design, so you can use it every day,
でも、ちょっとロゴも入っているので、とっても可愛いかなと思います
but it also features a subtle logo, which I think is very cute.
シンプルで、いつも持ち歩きやすく、でもおそろいにもできる
It's simple, easy to carry around, and lets us be matching.
ちょっとね、みんなバンダナはしないかな？と思ったので、ハンカチにしてみました
I thought maybe not everyone wears bandanas, so I made it a handkerchief instead.
みんなで私を持ち歩いてね！
Carry a piece of me with you!
そして続いては、こちら！
And next up is this one!
いつも一緒おでかけぬいバッグ！
The "Always Together Outing" Plush Bag!
ということで、こちらはパーカー衣装の私が乗った
So, this features me in my hoodie outfit,
ぬんぬん型のポーチを開けると、あんきも柄のバッグが出てくる
and when you open the Nun-Nun shaped pouch, an Ankimo-patterned bag comes out,
ぬいバッグということで
making it a plush bag.
なんかぬいぐるみのキーホルダーの感覚で、こう一緒に
You can use it like a plush keychain,
歩くこととか、カバンにつけること、痛バッグみたいにね
carrying it around or attaching it to your bag like an ita-bag,
つけることもできるし、持ち運べるし
so you can carry it around with you.
なんかグッズとか、こう「買いすぎちゃった！」って時に
And if you happen to buy too much merch on the go
「入らないな」って時に、ちょっと出して使えたりもすると思うので
and it won't fit, you can take out the bag and use it,
ぜひぜひ。これはね、ずっとあの、出してみたかったグッズなので
so please do! This is an item I've wanted to make for a long time,
みなさん見てもらえると嬉しいです
so I'd be really happy if you check it out.
そして最後は、こちら！
And finally, this one!
シチュエーションボイス「ライブの後で」！
Situation Voice: "After the Concert"!
ちょっとお茶目な私と、これからに向けて意気込みを語る
You can enjoy both a slightly playful side of me,
かっこいい私の両方が楽しめるボイスです！
and a cool side of me talking about my future determinations.
そして今回は、フルセットの特典が二つあるよ！
And this time, there are two full-set purchase bonuses!
まずはこちら！
First is this one!
ときのそら直筆サイン、プラス、箔押し複製メッセージ！
Tokino Sora's hand-signed, plus a foil-stamped printed message!
今回はですね、いつもなんですけど、数量限定なしでやるので
For this, there will be no limit on quantity,
ぜひ、みなさん、たくさんたくさん、サイン、書かせてください
so please let me write lots and lots of signatures for all of you.
心を込めて全部書くから、ぜひぜひ、いっぱい
I will sign each one with all my heart, so please
応募してね！
place your orders!
そしてもう一つの特典は、こちら！
And the other bonus is this!
昨年9月から販売された、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚つきます！
You'll get one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game, which went on sale last September!
フルセットを購入した人だけの、特別な、推しホロメンカードです
This is a special "oshi holomem" card, exclusive to those who buy the full set.
まだ遊んだことないよって人、ホロライブのオフィシャルカードゲームのホームページや
For those who haven't played it yet, you can check the Hololive Official Card Game website
カードの詳細や、遊び方を確認できるからぜひチェックしてね
to find details about the cards and how to play, so please check it out.
これでみんな、買ってくれるだろうな
I'm sure everyone will buy it now.
買ってくれよ！
You better buy it!
ということで以上、誕生日グッズでした！みんなよろしくね！
And that concludes the birthday merchandise intro! Thank you, everyone!
そして、二つ目のお知らせは！
And now, for the second announcement!
なんと！
Unbelievably...!
え、昨日？今日のなのかな？の0時に、え
Yesterday—or is it today?—at midnight,
デジタル配信が始まりました
the digital release began for
「Swallow Tail」のミュージックビデオ！
the music video of "Swallow Tail"!
なんと！
And amazingly...!
この後、プレミア公開です！
It will premiere right after this!
みんな、
Everyone,
みんなに感謝の気持ちを込めてMVを用意しておきました
I prepared this MV with all my gratitude to you all.
ぜひぜひみなさん、MVでも私の曲聞いてください！
So please listen to my song along with the MV!
これが嬉しい告知だよ！
This is the happy announcement!
え、こちら、曲のテーマというか、まあ、ちょっとね、爽やかな感じで
Regarding the song's theme, it has a fresh feel to it,
みんなへの感謝の気持ちを込めつつ、ちょっとね、切ない歌詞とかもあったりするので
conveying my gratitude to everyone, while also having some bittersweet lyrics,
とても、どうなんでしょう
so it's a very... how should I say,
MV発表が楽しみですね。ということですね
exciting MV release. That's the announcement!
え、この後21時15分からの予定なんですけど、すごくギリギリかもしれない
It's scheduled for 21:15 after this, but we might be cutting it close.
え、メインは21時半からになります
The main premiere will start at 21:30.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
というわけで、
So,
その曲、
that song...
最後に聞きたくない？
Don't you want to hear it at the end?
初めて生で歌います
I'll perform it live for the first time.
この曲で締めたいと思います
I'd like to end the stream with this song.
聞いてください、「Swallow Tail」
Please listen to "Swallow Tail".
澄み渡る青はいつも
Because the crystal blue sky always...
始まりを強く照らすから
...strongly shines on our new beginning,
本当は震えている
Even though my hands and feet...
手足が隠せないよ
...are trembling, and I can't hide it.
物語の先はどう？
How will the story continue?
君なら何色で描く？
What color would you paint it with?
むせび泣いた日のこと
Remembering the days I sobbed...
やめられなかった日のことを
...and the days I couldn't stop.
ツバメみたいに早く
If only I could fly...
飛べたらいいのに
...as fast as a swallow.
もう何もいらないから 忘れさせたりしないから
Because I don't need anything else,
どこまでも遠くへと
and I won't ever let you forget.
この手を繋いで
No matter how far we go, holding hands tight,
向かい風に涙を泳ぐように
as if swimming through tears against the headwind.
淡い闇を越えて
Overcoming the pale darkness,
歪な翼でも
even with our distorted wings,
踊ろうよ 無限の夏の空へ
let's dance toward the infinite summer sky!
あははは！みんなありがとう！
Ahahaha! Thank you, everyone!
無くした鍵は見つかった
I finally found the lost key,
燃えるゴミの日に出しちゃった
only to realize I threw it out on burnable trash day.
いつの間にか薄透けた
Before we knew it, it had worn thin—
君のスペシャルな夢の船
your very special dream ship.
子供みたいに青く
If only I could wish...
願えたらいいのに
...with childish innocence.
気が付けば檻の中で
But by the time I realized, I was inside a cage.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
胸の隅で傷んで泣くのは
The reason my heart aches and cries in the corner...
きっと大事なものだから
...is because it's surely something precious.
間違っても 彷徨っても
Even if we make mistakes or wander astray,
離さないでいよう
let's never let go.
空の果て 群青の
To the edge of the sky, beyond the ultramarine...
その先を見つめて
...gazing far ahead,
飛びたいの この命懸けて
I want to fly, risking my very life.
もう何もいらないから 忘れさせたりしないから普通に
Because I don't need anything else,
どこまでも遠くへと
and I won't ever let you forget.
ありのまま紡いで
Weaving our stories just as they are,
向かい風に涙を泳ぐように
as if swimming through tears against the headwind.
淡い闇を越えて
Overcoming the pale darkness,
歪な翼で行こう
let's go with our distorted wings,
無限の夏の空へ
toward the infinite summer sky!
今日見に来てくれてありがとう！これ、私とっても嬉しかったし、そらともも嬉しいぞ！
Thank you for coming to watch today! I'm so happy about this, and I'm sure you Soratomos are happy too!
ありがとうございました！ファンクラブの会員ライブも、メンバー限定だけど、よかったら来てね！
Thank you so much! Our fan club member-only live is coming up, please join if you can!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!